<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Deliberate Risk Blog</title>
    <link>http://deliberaterisk.com/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Deliberate Risk Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 14:02:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://deliberaterisk.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the Deliberate Risk Blog</title>
      <link>http://deliberaterisk.com/post/firstpost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 14:02:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://deliberaterisk.com/post/firstpost/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my new blog, DeliberateRisk.com! My goal is to use this blog as a platform to document my ideas on risk and risk management. When we think of risk and risk management we usually think of financial risk management (e.g., insurance, banking, enterprise) and certainty these are areas that I have a strong interest in. However given this is my personal blog, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to be so narrow in my exploration of the concepts of risk. Through this blog, I&amp;rsquo;ll explore risk in all aspects of life, from career development to fitness &amp;amp; health; from raising kids to rest &amp;amp; relaxation. Although inquiries into these areas may not benefit me monetarily, I will gain so many intangible benefits including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A greater understanding of risk metrics;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A better appreciation of unquantifiable risks;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deliberate practice with statistical methods and models; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An Improvement in my overall writing skills.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My goal for this blog is pretty simple:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a living repository of my work as it relates to the study of risk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Display my competency in the area of data and risk analysis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Demonstrate how risk management is applicable outside of the financial and business enterprise disciplines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create practical applications of risk management as it relates
to a wide range of topics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Share interesting information (e.g., articles, books, podcasts, etc..) that contribute to the conversation of risk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, this blog is my way of pursuing excellence, as stated so eloquently in the book the Just City by Jo Walton.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope that overtime, the work that I pursue through this blog will lead me to to a:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deeper understanding of the theoretical basis of risk management, related to statistics, philosophy, finance, fitness, and phycology(to name a few); and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Act as an intellectual escape leading to my continued enjoyment of life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://deliberaterisk.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 14:01:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://deliberaterisk.com/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I know this game got valleys and peaks&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expectation for dips,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For precipitation we stack chips, hardly&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jay - Z Can I Live&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My name is Jarvis Alexander and I see the ideas of risk management discussed in all parts of life, even the music I listen to. DeliberateRisk.com my attempt to memorialize my ideas and research in the
areas of risk measurement and risk management. Although the concepts and tools will be similar to what is utilized in the financial sector, I will not discuss financial topics in my blog. Instead, I wish to explore how we can use risk management tools in various parts of our life, from health and fitness, to productivity and happiness. While I admit that there is nothing novel about my approach, my hope is that writings will positively contribute to the discourse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you think about it or not
the application of risk management is an important part of everyone&amp;rsquo;s life. Like it or not, most decisions have some sort or risk analysis component to it. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re shopping for groceries, going to the gym, or working at a job,
every aspect of our life entails a risk decision. I want this blog to be an exploration on the computer concepts that involve risk measurement, and risk decisions. This blog will act as a journal of the theories I wish to understand,
ideas I would like to explore, and risk analysis and assessment of which I would like to master. I&amp;rsquo;m going to play around with applying the concept
of deliberate risk to all areas of ones life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workflow</title>
      <link>http://deliberaterisk.com/Workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 14:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://deliberaterisk.com/Workflow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Comming Soon&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Risk Vocabulary</title>
      <link>http://deliberaterisk.com/risk_vocab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 14:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://deliberaterisk.com/risk_vocab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cfainstitute.org/learning/tools/glossary/Pages/index.aspx&#34;&gt;CFA Glossary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;risk&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Likely&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unlikely&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ex ante&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ex post&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fitness&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;risk alignment&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fitness&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;asset&lt;/strong&gt;: An asset is anything tangible or intangible that is capable
of being owned or produced to create value. In this case we are talking about
investments. An asset class is a group of assets with similar attributes.
Asset classes are not highly correlated with each other and asset with each
class can only fit into one class. Finally, the sum of all assets in each
class should cover the majority of investable assets and contain a sufficient
number of liquid investable assets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>