<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Deliberate Risk Blog</title>
    <link>http://deliberaterisk.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Deliberate Risk Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 19:51:17 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://deliberaterisk.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the Deliberate Risk Blog</title>
      <link>http://deliberaterisk.com/post/firstpost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 19:51:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://deliberaterisk.com/post/firstpost/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my new blog DeliberateRisk.com! My goal is to use this blog as
a platform to document my ideas on risk and risk management. When we think
of risk and risk management we using think of financial risk management (e.g.,
insurance, banking, enterprise) and certainty those are areas that I have
a strong interest in. However given this is my personal blog, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to
be so narrow in my exploration in the concepts of risk. Through this blog, I&amp;rsquo;ll
explore risk in all aspects of life, from career development to fitness &amp;amp; health,
and from raising kids to rest &amp;amp; relaxation. Although inquiries into these areas
may not benefit me monetarily, I believe that the intangible benefit in relation
to:
* A greater understanding the known risk in these areas;
* A better appreciation of the unquantifiable risks;
* Practicing statistical methods; and
* Improving my writing skills in different styles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My goal for this blog is pretty simple:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a living repository of my work as it relates to the study of risk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Display my competency in the area of data and risk analysis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Demonstrate how risk management is applicable outside of the financial
and business enterprise scope.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create practical applications of risk management as it relates
to a wide range of topics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Share interesting information (e.g., articles, books, podcasts, etc..)
that contribute to the conversation of risk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, this blog is my way of pursuing  excellence, as stated so
eloquently in the book the Just City by Jo Walton.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope that overtime, the work that purse through this blog wil:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved writing skills, both technical and creative;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deeper understanding in the theoretical basis of risk management, general
involving statistics, philosophy, finance, fitness, and
phycology(to name a few); and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Me having fun, and continuing to enjoy life to the fullest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://deliberaterisk.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://deliberaterisk.com/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;DeliberateRisk.com is an attempt to memorialize my ideas and research into
areas of risk measurement and risk management.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>