<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Deliberate Risk Blog</title>
    <link>http://deliberaterisk.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Deliberate Risk Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2016 15:50:19 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://deliberaterisk.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>What Language Are You Speaking?</title>
      <link>http://deliberaterisk.com/post/language_are_you_speaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2016 15:50:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://deliberaterisk.com/post/language_are_you_speaking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Before I start exploring the concepts or risk, I need address
how I define commonly used jargon. Essentially,
I want to create a risk vocabulary in which readers can more
clearly understand my work based on how I am using specific words.
 In most instances, this will not be an issue. My goal is to make my
 writing clear and concise. I will strive to use
simpler words and shorter sentences. However, there are certainty commonly
used jargon that I won&amp;rsquo;t be able to avoid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general, any terms that I use will follow the definition
presented in the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cfainstitute.org/learning/tools/glossary/Pages/index.aspx&#34;&gt;CFA Glossary&lt;/a&gt;.
Throughout my writing I will refer various
CFA articles and quote relevant CFA publications when explaining financial
concepts. Mainly because I am a CFA charter holder and a vast majority of my
fundamental knowledge in the area of risk management comes from the study
material that I used while I was a CFA candidate. But also because the CFA
institute and its members have consistently demonstrated a high level of
expertise in various financial subjects and this has translated into the
production of well regarded research and publications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of constantly linking back to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cfainstitute.org/learning/tools/glossary/Pages/index.aspx&#34;&gt;CFA Glossary&lt;/a&gt;,
as I continue to write on various subjects, when there are certain words
or concepts that I either frequently reference or have become the basis to
important discussions I will define them on the &amp;ldquo;Risk Vocabulary&amp;rdquo; page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similar to all of my work on this blog, the
&lt;a href=&#34;www.deliberaterisk.com/risk-vocab/&#34;&gt;Risk Vocabulary page&lt;/a&gt; is a work in
progress. My hope is that it will always be forward progress.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the Deliberate Risk Blog</title>
      <link>http://deliberaterisk.com/post/firstpost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 19:51:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://deliberaterisk.com/post/firstpost/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my new blog DeliberateRisk.com! My goal is to use this blog as
a platform to document my ideas on risk and risk management. When we think
of risk and risk management we using think of financial risk management (e.g.,
insurance, banking, enterprise) and certainty those are areas that I have
a strong interest in. However given this is my personal blog, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to
be so narrow in my exploration in the concepts of risk. Through this blog, I&amp;rsquo;ll
explore risk in all aspects of life, from career development to fitness &amp;amp; health,
and from raising kids to rest &amp;amp; relaxation. Although inquiries into these areas
may not benefit me monetarily, I believe that the intangible benefit in relation
to:
* A greater understanding the known risk in these areas;
* A better appreciation of the unquantifiable risks;
* Practicing statistical methods; and
* Improving my writing skills in different styles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My goal for this blog is pretty simple:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a living repository of my work as it relates to the study of risk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Display my competency in the area of data and risk analysis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Demonstrate how risk management is applicable outside of the financial
and business enterprise scope.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create practical applications of risk management as it relates
to a wide range of topics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Share interesting information (e.g., articles, books, podcasts, etc..)
that contribute to the conversation of risk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, this blog is my way of pursuing  excellence, as stated so
eloquently in the book the Just City by Jo Walton.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope that overtime, the work that purse through this blog wil:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved writing skills, both technical and creative;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deeper understanding in the theoretical basis of risk management, general
involving statistics, philosophy, finance, fitness, and
phycology(to name a few); and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Me having fun, and continuing to enjoy life to the fullest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>